

Curriculum Vitae for Jonathan Feinberg

Personal information

Address: Wessels Gate 9A E-mail: jonathan@xal.no

0165 Oslo Phone: +47 932 14 474

Born: 28.04.1984

Summary

I am specialist in probability theory, statistics and machine learning with heavy focus on numerical programming and practical applications. I am highly analytical in my thinking and quickly can breaks down open ended complex problems into solvable components. I am also well versed as a programmer, with expert level experience in the Python programming language.

Technical skills

Frameworks Armadillo, GIS, Keras/Tensorflow, Matplotlib, NumPy/SciPy, Pandas,

PyMC, Scikit-Learn, Statsmodels, XGBoost

Languages Bash, C, C++, Latex, MATLAB, Python, R, RST/Markdown, Vim-

script

Tools CircleCl, Docker, Git, Linux, OSX, Regular Expression, Sphinx

Education

2015 Ph.D. in Mathematics from the Department of Mathematics, Univer-

sity of Oslo

Thesis: "Some Improvements and Applications and Non-intrusive Po-

lynomial Chaos Expansions"

Supervisor: Professor Hans Petter Langtangen

2009 M.Sc. in Modelling and Data Analysis from the Department of Mathe-

matics, University of Oslo

Thesis: "Threshold Definition of Early Warning Systems to Natural

Hazards"

Supervisor: Professor Bent Natvig

2007 B.Sc. in Mathematics, Informatics and Technology, University of Oslo

Professional experience

2016 -	Consultant at Expert Analytics
2016 - 2018	Guest lecturer at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Teaching Position at the Department of Informatics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2015	Private tutor at high school and under-graduate level at House of
	Math
2014 - 2015	Scientific Programmer for Simula Research Laboratory
2013 - 2014	Consultant at Kalkulo AS
2011 - 2014	Ph.D. student at Simula Research Laboratory
2009 - 2010	Research Assistant at Texas A&M University
2009 - 2009	Science Teacher at Smerud Medical Research
2008	Assistant Teacher at Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo
2007 - 2008	Student Ambassador at Public Relations and Events Office, University
	of Oslo
2007	Data Analyst at If P&C Insurance

Languages

English Fluent

Norwegian Mother tongue

Personal skills

Communication Able to convey research and condensed knowledge into a presentable

and explainable form. Extensive experience as university lecturer and

teacher.

Planning I am a "Problem solver", able to see strengths and weaknesses of

proposed progress plans, grounded in fact-based thought.

Technology Large enthusiasm for learning and mastering anything new within

science, technology and programming.

Some interests and hobbies

Personal Traveling, Gin tasting

Tech Bayesian Statistics/Probabilistic Modelling, Open Source Software,

Machine Learning, Global Optimization Algorithms, Python program-

ming

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity NEC Oncoimmunity

Role Senior Developer and Data Scientist

Staffing 20 Developers/Data Scientists/Bioinformatitions

Description Oncolmmunity develop bioinformatics software that has the ability

to empower precision cancer immunotherapy, and thus improves the outlook for patients with late-stage disease. My role is to develop machine-learning methods applied to genomic data for tumor immune profiling. The goal is to select optimal patients to be assigned to cancer

immunotherapy clinical trials.

Tools Python, Keras/Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, XGBoost

Activity Statkraft
Role Data Scientist
Staffing 3 developers

Description Statkraft is a leading company in hydropower internationally, and

Europe's largest generator of renewable energy. Our role was to explore the possibility of applying machine learning to parts of Statkraft's core business. In particular, we looked into various machine learning techniques that could be used to predict future market energy consume. The techniques included applying methods like statistical regression,

time-series models, and artificial neural networks.

Tools Python, Keras/Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Statsmodels

Activity Matlab to C++ converter

Role Software developer Staffing 2 developers

Description As part of an EU sponsored project, Simula Research Laboratory and

WesternGeco is collaborating to speed up the code translation step from Matlab to C++ using Armadillo. The approach involves creating a full parser that creates semi-automatic translations. I contributed as

the developer of the parser, and the structure of translation.

Tools Python, Armadillo, Sphinx

Activity Chaospy – Uncertainty Quantification Toolbox

Role Software Maintainer

Staffing 2 developers

Description Chaospy is an actively maintained open source toolbox containing a

large collection of uncertainty quantification tools. It also include some state-of-the-art tools designed to reduce the computational budget in analysis. Chaospy is currently used as numerical engine in multiple

research and development projects.

https://github.com/jonathf/chaospy

Tools Python, NumPy, SciPy

Activity Numpoly – Multivariate polynomials as NumPy datatype

Role Software Maintainer

Staffing 1 developer

Description Numpoly is an open source library for creating, manipulating polyno-

mial arrays. The library provides a subclass of numpy.ndarray implemented to represent polynomials as array element. As such it is fast and scales very well with the size of the coefficients, in addition to it

being compatible with most numpy functionalities.

https://github.com/jonathf/numpoly

Tools Python, NumPy